(
"ai_sub_version": "1.9.1",
"subtitles_prompt_version": 2,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": "gemini-cli:gemini-3-flash-preview",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600
)
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": true,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"encoder": "libx264"
)
),
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"subtitles": 8
),
"retry": (
"run": 3,
"max": 9,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": false,
"scrub": true
)
YOZORA MEL BIRTHDAY LIVE
October 31 YOZORA MEL BIRTHDAY
Halloween Princess ハロウィンのお姫様
Halloween Princess
我儘姫 作詞・作曲：ふじを
Wagamama Hime
Lyrics/Composition: Fujio
1, 2, 3 不思議なステップで
1, 2, 3, with mysterious steps...
踊り出すビート 宵に輝くネオンの下で光る
...the beat starts dancing, shining under the evening neon lights.
私、可愛い？可愛い？お召使いたち あの子はどこに？
Am I cute? Cute? My servants, where is that girl?
うだうだ ごたごた どらどら ぎゃんぎゃん 何も知ることない
Idle chatter, trouble, sluggishly, noisily, there's nothing you need to know.
甘い甘いチョコが食べたい
I want to eat sweet, sweet chocolate.
熱い熱いラテが飲みたい
I want to drink hot, hot latte.
ホクホクのパンが食べたいな ダメ？
I want to eat warm, fluffy bread. Is that no good?
とろとろのチーズが食べたい
I want to eat gooey cheese.
ふかふかのベッドで寝たい
I want to sleep in a soft bed.
うとうと おやすみなさい UPPY
Dozing off, good night. UPPY.
わがまま ラン・ラン・ラン・ラン
Selfish run-run-run-run,
私のこと笑わないで 私、可愛いでしょ？
don't laugh at me. I'm cute, aren't I?
お願い GIVE GIVE GIVE EVERYTHING あたいを助けて
Please GIVE GIVE GIVE EVERYTHING, help me.
何もかも許される
Everything is forgiven.
だって私が一番可愛いんだから
Because I'm the cutest one of all.
3, 2, 1 香ばしい匂いで
3, 2, 1, with a savory scent...
おびき出すビート 宵に月明かりの下で 誰をやる？
...the beat lures you out, under the evening moonlight, who will you do it to?
ギロチン 銃殺 火あぶり 切腹 お好きなオプションで
Guillotine, execution by shooting, burning at the stake, seppuku, with your favorite option.
誰も私には逆らえない つまらない
No one can defy me. How boring.
苦い苦いキモが食べたい
I want to eat bitter, bitter liver.
赤い赤いスープ飲みたい
I want to drink red, red soup.
ホクホクお肉食べたいの さあ
I want to eat warm, juicy meat. Now...
甘い甘いそれじゃ足りない
Sweet, sweet things are not enough.
油断した面も見せて
Show me your unguarded face.
ラランララランラララン ホラ まだまだまだまだ足りないわ
La-lan-la-la-lan-la-la-lan, see, it's still not enough.
わがまま 私のこと愛してくれる
Selfish, waiting for someone...
誰かを待っているの
...who will love me.
孤独な夜空に一人 惑うフリをして
Alone in the lonely night sky, pretending to be lost.
...妄想も七度目...
...delusions for the seventh time...
だって私がね
Because I'm, you know,
ジャック・オー・ランタンたりとも怖がらないで
not even afraid of Jack-o'-lanterns,
私、可愛そうでしょう？
don't I look so pitifully cute?
お願い kiss give me 全て与え続けて
Please, kiss give me, keep giving me everything,
何もかも許される
everything will be forgiven.
やっぱ私が一番可愛いんだから
After all, I'm the cutest one of all!
Myth or Treat
作詞：Calliope Mori　作曲：Farhan Sarasin
和訳：datenkou & 夜空メル
Lyrics: Calliope Mori  Composition: Farhan Sarasin
JP Translation: datenkou & Yozora Mel
Trick or treat
キミの推しはクローゼットの中でドッキリを仕掛けた
Your oshi has set up a prank inside the closet.
TRICK OR TREAT ほら もうキャンディーはない
TRICK OR TREAT! Look, the candy is all gone.
お腹がいっぱい？じゃあ、チェーンソーの出番かな？
Is your stomach full? Then maybe it's the chainsaw's turn?
みんなが取り憑かれた その仮説を確かめよう 解剖しよう
Everyone's possessed! Let's check that hypothesis and dissect it.
踊れ、隠れないで泣き虫
Dance! Don't hide away, you crybaby.
幻影のない HALLOWEEN は面白くない Haha
HALLOWEEN without illusions is no fun! Haha!
みんなが照れている
Everyone is shyly blushing.
かわいい
How cute.
熱くなった血をくれるでしょう？
You'll give me your feverish blood, won't you?
Myth or Treat
あぁ、呪いの配信
Ah, a cursed stream.
びびって叫んじゃえ！
Get scared and scream it out!
見せるよ今夜だけ まだ見ぬ恐ろしい顔を
I'll show you, just for tonight, a terrifying face you've never seen.
なんてガチ恋 NIGHT
What a serious-love NIGHT!
魔女たちの出番だ
It's time for the witches to shine!
もう逃げられないよ 捧げてキミの魂を
You can't escape anymore! Surrender your soul to us.
踊りだせ TONIGHT
Start dancing TONIGHT!
見て恐ろしい SIGHT
Behold the terrifying SIGHT!
腹ペコだ、食べたいねぇ、ちょうだい？
I'm starving, I want to eat, can I have some?
曲でビビらせて 一緒に歌おう
Let the song scare you, and let's sing together!
「嫁」じゃなくて かぼちゃよ DING-DONG?
Not a 'wife', but a pumpkin! DING-DONG?
墓場で待ってる
I'll be waiting in the graveyard.
覚悟できてる？
Are you prepared?
我らの歌で盛り上がるがいい！ベー！ふふっ
Get hyped up with our song! Bleh! Hehe.
おびえて叫べ！ MYTH が暴れる これぞ我らのスタイル
Be terrified and scream! MYTH is running wild! This is our style!
イェーイ！イェーイ！
Yay! Yay!
やったー、楽しかったー！
I did it! That was so much fun!
すごかった！いい曲だったね！最高！
That was amazing! It's a great song! The best!
本当にまさかこの曲歌えるのめっちゃ嬉しい！
I'm so happy we could actually sing this song!
あぁ、早く私も3Dで踊りたいよ！
Ah, I want to dance in 3D soon too!
見たい！ホロライブインドネシアの3D早く見たい！
I want to see it! I want to see Hololive Indonesia's 3D soon!
いつになれるの？
When will it be ready?
分かんない！
I don't know!
分かんないけど楽しみにしてて！
I don't know, but please look forward to it!
でもなんか今日 2D だけどさ、いい感じに後ろに...ね？
But even though you're in 2D today, you're in the back in a good way... right?
確かに！画面がすごい！
True! The screen is amazing!
デカい！
It's huge!
デカいね私たち。巨人！
We're huge. Like giants!
おぉ、すごい！
Oh, wow!
この「Myth or Treat」は元々 EN のみんなで英語で歌った曲だったんだけど...
This 'Myth or Treat' was originally a song that everyone in EN sang in English...
日本語でまさか歌えるなんて思ってなかったです。嬉しい。
I never thought we'd be singing it in Japanese. I'm so happy.
う、メルもこの曲さ、聞いた時からめっちゃ大好きな曲だったから嬉しいよ。
Mel too, I've loved this song ever since I first heard it, so I'm happy.
日本語版すごい自然に聞こえて、すごく歌いやすかった。すごかった。
The Japanese version sounds so natural and was very easy to sing. It was amazing.
だよね！結構自分でね、「これやったら可愛いかな？」っていう風にちょっと直してみた。
Right! I actually revised it a bit myself, thinking "would this be cute?"
おぉ、すごい！自分で！？
Oh, amazing! By yourself!?
すごい！メル様のこの誕生日に歌うっていうのもなかなかじゃないですか？
Amazing! Singing it on Mel-sama's birthday is quite something, isn't it?
嬉しい！やっぱハロウィンだからさ、ぴったりだよね、この曲ね。
I'm so happy! Since it's Halloween, this song is perfect, right?
メル様、お誕生日おめでとう！
Mel-sama, Happy Birthday!
ありがとうございます！やったー！
Thank you so much! Yay!
Happy Birthday!
この後も色々あるんじゃないですか？
There's more to come after this, right?
そうなんだよ、まだ二曲目だからさ...
That's right, it's only the second song...
なんか帰る感じ？
Are we leaving?
いや今日ね、ハロウィンだから魔界の通りたちは、お菓子いっぱいもらいに行かないといけないんですよ。
Well today is Halloween, so the Underworld residents have to go get lots of treats.
え？ちょっと待って、ずっと魔界にいたからさ、めちゃめちゃしてたチョコ、お腹空いた。
Wait a sec, we've been in the Underworld this whole time, my stomach is growling for chocolate.
ああ分かる、メルもお腹空いた。
Ah, I get it. Mel's hungry too.
食べに行っちゃう？食べに行っちゃう？
Shall we go eat? Shall we go eat?
ちょっと待って！メルも行きたい！
Wait a minute! Mel wants to go too!
ねえ、ずるい！メルも！
Hey, that's unfair! Mel too!
待って待って待って！
Wait, wait, wait!
行かないで！
Don't go!
置いていかないで、待ってー！
Don't leave me behind, wait!
頑張ってねー！
Good luck!
行っちゃったよ。頑張ってねって。
They just left... saying "Good luck."
えー、本当に、もう寂しいじゃん。
Eh... it's really lonely now.
あ、でも今日はね、かぷみんのみんながいるよね。
Ah, but today, all the Kapumin are here, right?
よし！改めてみんな...
Alright! Once again, everyone...
こんかぷー！魔界の天才バンパイア、夜空メルでーす！
Konkapu! The Underworld's genius vampire, Yozora Mel!
今日は最後まで楽しんでいってください。
Please enjoy until the end today.
そしてそして、#夜空メル爆誕2022 でいっぱいツイートしてね。
And, and, tweet a lot with #YozoraMelBirthday2022!
写真もバシャバシャ撮ってください。
Please take lots of photos too.
後でメル見に行くからな。約束だよ。
Mel will check them out later. It's a promise!
この後もまだまだコラボとかソロ曲とかたくさん続くので、ぜひぜひ最後まで楽しんでいってください。
After this, there are still many collabs and solo songs to come, so please, please enjoy until the very end.
よし！それじゃあ、この後も一緒に楽しんでいくぞー！
Alright! Well then, let's continue to enjoy the rest together! Let's go!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Attention! Cover! Lie down! Halt!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Attention! Cover! Lie down! Halt!
戦場へ 前世へ そして死の淵まで
命捨てたその覚悟を示せ
To the battlefield, to the front line, and even to the brink of death.
Show the resolution of one who has cast aside their life.
震えるだろう あの砲声が
抵抗もする うちの声だ
You must be trembling, that roar of cannon fire.
It's our voice of resistance.
踏み潰せ 踏み潰せ
Crush them! Crush them!
諸君、我々の任務は何だ？殲滅だ！
生き残り残らずの殲滅だ！
Soldiers, what is our mission? Annihilation!
Complete annihilation with no survivors!
為すべき事はただ一つ 地獄を創れ！
There is only one thing to do. Create hell!
弾丸の雨に打たれに行くのか
笑止千万 帝国の為だ！
Are you going to be struck by the rain of bullets?
How ridiculous, it's for the Empire!
戦場へ 前世へ そして死の淵まで
命捨てた覚悟を示せよ
To the battlefield, to the front line, and even to the brink of death.
Show the resolution of one who has cast aside their life.
忠誠を 純情を そしてその魂を
全て捧げ勝ち鬨を上げよ
Loyalty, devotion, and even your very soul.
Sacrifice everything and raise a cry of victory.
さあ其処に築いてみせろ
天に届く死体の山を
Now, build it there.
A mountain of corpses reaching to the heavens.
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Attention! Cover! Lie down! Halt!
どこに興味があると言うんだ
見ろ死肉が花火のようだ
Where do you think your interest lies?
Look, the dead flesh is like fireworks.
撒き散らす 撒き散らす
Scatter it! Scatter it!
千の傷跡忘れちゃいないさ
炎の熱も零れた脳（おもい）も
I'll never forget the thousand scars.
Not the heat of the flames, nor the spilled brains.
最期の呻きも濁った瞳も
嗚呼それこそを求めるのだ
Not the final groans, nor the clouded eyes.
Ah, that is exactly what we seek.
憐れも屁も まして我が灼く
敵は牙を捨てた飼い犬の所業
Pity and farts, let alone my scorching.
The enemy's deeds are those of a pet dog that threw away its fangs.
絶望と動乱を懸けた正気の沙汰は
地獄よりも楽園のようだ
An act of sanity bet on despair and upheaval
is like a paradise more than hell.
その四肢は踊る為に
踊り狂う為有るのだ！
Those limbs exist for dancing.
They exist for dancing madly!
見える価値など無い 価値なき者同士の争いに
命の徒花咲かせてみせろ
There is no visible value. In a conflict between worthless things,
make the ephemeral flowers of life bloom.
法律も秩序でも
狂った奴が創ってる
Laws and order alike
are made by madmen.
まさに笑劇不条理だけの
起承転結
Truly a farce, an introduction-development-twist-conclusion
of nothing but absurdity.
戦場へ 前世へ そして死の淵まで
命捨てた覚悟を示せ
To the battlefield, to the front line, and even to the brink of death.
Show the resolution of one who has cast aside their life.
忠誠を 純情を そしてその魂を
全て捧げ勝ち鬨を上げよ
Loyalty, devotion, and even your very soul.
Sacrifice everything and raise a cry of victory.
さあ其処に築いてみせろ
天に届く死体の山に
Now, build it there.
Into a mountain of corpses reaching to the heavens.
谺す憎しみさえ
掻き消す爆発を
An explosion that drowns out
even the echoing hatred.
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Cover! Get down! Stop!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Cover! Get down! Stop!
Feuer! Sperrfeuer! Los!
Fire! Barrage! Go!
Achtung! Deckung! Hinlegen! Halt!
Attention! Cover! Get down! Stop!
メル先輩誕生日おめでとう！
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
ラプラスちゃんありがとう！
Laplus-chan, thank you!
なかなかカッコよく決まったんじゃない？
Didn't we look pretty cool just now?
まあ元々カッコいいっすけどね、へへへ。
Well, I've always been cool, hehehe.
お、おん...
O-oh...
こんなにさ、ちっちゃいのにびっくりしちゃうメル。
I'm surprised by how small you are.
いや、ちっちゃい。
Really, small.
ちっちゃいって何言ってんすか！ほら！
Small? What are you saying! Look!
これ見て！ツノ、ツノ、ツノ！ほらほら！
Look at this! Horns, horns, horns! See? See?
ちょっと比べてみよっか。
Let's compare for a bit.
何... ああ、いいですけど。
What... Oh, okay.
ほら、ね？
Look, see?
あ、待って。
Ah, wait.
あ、待てよ、これメルのアホ毛あるからメルの勝ちじゃない？
Ah, wait, since I have an ahoge, I'm taller. I win!
いやメルの勝ち。はいメルの勝ち。はいメルの勝ち。
No, I win. Yes, I win. Yes, I win.
イエーイ！やったー！
Yay! I did it!
いーいーいー...
Fine, fine, fine...
メル先輩...
Mel-senpai...
でもさ、ラプラスちゃんちっちゃいのは可愛いからいいんじゃない？
But Laplus-chan being small is cute, so isn't it fine?
いや、なんか丸め込もうとしてますよね？
No, you're just trying to smooth things over, aren't you?
あ、そうだ！
Oh, right!
あ、ちょっと話聞いてなくね？
Ah, are you even listening to me?
せっかくカッコいい歌歌ったんだし、さ、2人でちょっとカッコいい決めポーズ取らん？
Since we sang a cool song, want to strike a cool pose together?
おお、いいっすね！あ、いいよやろうやろう！
Oh, that sounds great! Yeah, let's do it!
行くぞ人間達！バッチリスクショ撮るのだぞ！
Listen up, humans! Make sure you take some great screenshots!
お、撮るのだぞー。
Oh, take them!
よし、じゃあ、まずは... そうだな。
Okay, then, first... let's see.
片手を、て、手をパーにして...
Put one hand out, like an open palm...
そうそうそう、突き出す感じ！
Right, right, right, like you're thrusting it out!
おお、いいじゃないっすか！必殺技みたい！
Oh, looking good! It's like a special move!
はっ！
Ha!
カッコよくない？
Doesn't it look cool?
おー、いいんじゃなーい？
Oh, looking good!
括目せよ。
Witness this.
いいじゃん。
Nice.
ラプメル！
Lap-Mel!
いいね。あ、いいっすね。
Nice. Yeah, that's good.
他やる？
Want to do another one?
次いいわよ。
Sure, let's do another.
じゃあ、次は腕組みして、背中合わせで...
Next, let's cross our arms and stand back-to-back...
おお、いいね！少年漫画の王道...
Oh, nice! A shonen manga classic...
待って待って、めっちゃツノ邪魔、ラプラスちゃん。
Wait, wait, the horns are really in the way, Laplus-chan.
あ、ちょっと、お、すみません、すみません。
Ah, sorry, sorry about that.
邪魔！ツノ邪魔！
In the way! The horns are in the way!
メル映ってない！
I'm not in the shot!
メルさんちょっと服がエロいんで、なんか、また...
Mel-san, your outfit is a bit too sexy, so...
ヴァンパイアにならないようにね！気をつけてくださいよ。
Make sure you don't turn into a vampire! Please be careful.
これ我輩の気遣いね、これ。ほら。
This is just my consideration for you. See?
見て？
Look at this?
はあ？どかないから！
Huh? I'm not moving!
いやなんでなんでなんで！
Wait, why why why!
このツノ、わ、いいから！
These horns, geez, fine!
邪魔！やめて！
They're in the way! Stop it!
どきな！
Move!
おい、あ、ほら！メルさんちょっと！
Hey, ah, look! Mel-san, wait!
こちら、幸福安心委員会です。
This is the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee.
どうして
Why is it
みんなが
that everyone
幸せなの
is so happy?
この世界のこと
About this world,
聞きたいって
I want to ask,
知りたいって
I want to know.
水辺の公園で
In the park by the water,
みんなが耳を澄ませて
everyone is listening closely,
わくわくするね
isn't it exciting?
ねえ、オンディーヌ？
Hey, Ondine?
ハイハーイ！
Hi hi!
さあさあ、みなさん
Now then, everyone,
教えてあげまーす！
I will tell you!
みんなが気になってること
The things everyone is curious about,
疑問に思ってること
the things everyone is wondering about,
全部教えてあげまーす！
I'll tell you all about it!
えー、みなさんが
Well, the fact that you all
幸福なのは... 義務なんです。
are happy... is your duty.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
我々、幸福安心委員会は
We, the Happiness and Peace of Mind Committee,
みなさまの幸せを願い
wish for everyone's happiness
支えまーす！
and will support you!
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty.
幸福なのは義務なんです
Being happy is a duty.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty.
ですから、安心して義務を果たすように！
So, please fulfill your duty with peace of mind!
みなさまの幸せが、我々の幸せ。
Your happiness is our happiness.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ？
It's a duty.
果たしてますか？
Are you fulfilling it?
幸せじゃないなら...
If you aren't happy...
絞首、斬首、銃殺、釜茹で、
Hanging, beheading, shooting, boiling,
溺死、電気、火あぶり、
drowning, electrocution, burning,
生き埋め、薬殺、石打ち、
burying alive, poisoning, stoning,
鋸、磔。
sawing, crucifixion.
好きなのを選んでね！
Choose whichever one you like!
ハイハーイ！
Hi hi!
さあさあ、みなさん
Now then, everyone,
幸せだけが満ちてまーす！
Only happiness fills this place!
不安とか不満
Anxiety or dissatisfaction,
何一つないでしょ？
there's none of that, right?
怖い
It's scary.
怖いよ
It's so scary...
幸せすぎて、怖いよ。
I'm so happy it's scary.
本当にみんなが幸せなの？
Is everyone really happy?
みんなが幸せなの？
Is everyone happy?
この世界の空の外
Outside the sky of this world
行きたいって、逃げたいって
Saying I want to go, saying I want to flee
水辺の公園でみんなが
At the park by the water, everyone...
耳を塞いでビクビクしてた
...was plugging their ears and trembling.
ねえ、ウンディーネ？
Hey, Undine?
ハイハーイ！
Hi, hi!
さあさあ、みなさん！死にました！
Now then, everyone! You've died!
オンディーヌを振った騎士は死にました！
The knight who dumped Undine has died!
葬儀に出るなら、向こうに並べ！
If you're attending the funeral, line up over there!
それ以外は幸せに暮らせ！
Other than that, live happily!
以上、幸福なのは義務なんです
That's all, being happy is a duty.
幸せですか？
Are you happy?
義務ですよ。
It's a duty, you know.
義務なんです。
It's a duty.
義務ですよ？
It's a duty, you know?
義務なんです。
It's a duty.
幸福なのは義務なんです。
Being happy is a duty.
義務なんです。
It's a duty.
義務ですよ。
It's a duty, you know.
義務なんです。
It's a duty.
幸せじゃないなら...
If you're not happy...
死ね。
Die.
一緒に怒られて、一緒に大きくなって
Getting scolded together, growing up together
一緒に涙して、その分もっと笑った
Crying together, laughing even more for that
仲良しの姉妹で隠し事はなかった
Close sisters, we had no secrets
好きな人の話、いつか聞きたいかも
I might want to hear about the person you like someday
突然どうしたの？うちら仲良しだけど
What happened all of a sudden? We're close, but...
大人になるほどね、秘密増やしていいの
As we become adults, it's okay to have more secrets
よそはよそ芸能関係
The outside world is entertainment business
爽やかな王子様？
A refreshing prince?
どうしよう全然違うし
What should I do, it's completely different
だけどいいの王子様
But it's fine, the prince
ぶりっ子して
Acting cute
ほっぺついて
Puffing out cheeks
ポーズ決めて
Striking a pose
アップしよう
Let's upload
大好きだよ
I love you
見つめ合って
Gazing at each other
可愛いねって、可愛いねって
Saying 'you're cute', 'you're cute'
苦手なこと、得意なこと
Things we're bad at, things we're good at
好みだとか、それぞれじゃん？
Preferences and such, they're all different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you
ケンカしても
Even if we fight
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll always be together
ルルレリラ
Lulurelila
こちらの方ですが、お付き合いをしてます
As for this person, we're dating
イメージ真逆でもちゃんと仲良くしてね
Even if our images are opposites, please get along well
取られたくないから少し拗ねてみたけど
I don't want you to be taken, so I sulked a bit
ホント楽しそうで私も嬉しくなった
You look so happy, and it made me happy too
気になる人とかいないの？お姉ちゃんに教えて
Is there anyone you're interested in? Tell your big sister
今更の恋愛は禁止、今はダメ夢のため
No dating now, it's not allowed, for the sake of our dreams
決めておいて
Decide it
ケンカして
Fighting
泣き笑いを
Laughter and tears
アップしよう
Let's upload
大好きだよ
I love you
見つめ合って
Gazing at each other
可愛いねって、可愛いねって
Saying 'you're cute', 'you're cute'
似ているとこ
Similarities
似てないとこ
Differences
趣味だとかさ
Hobbies and such
それぞれじゃん？
They're all different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you
仲直りも
Making up too
きっとすぐできる
I'm sure we can do it soon
ルルレリラ
Lulurelila
一ツ屋根の下で
Under one roof
明日も騒が...
Tomorrow will also be nois...
ぶりっこして
Acting cute
ほっぺつけて
Pressing cheeks together
ポーズ決めて
Striking a pose
アップしよう
Let's upload it
大好きだよ
I love you
見つめ合って
Gazing at each other
可愛いね
So cute
苦手な事
Things we're bad at
得意な事
Things we're good at
好みのとか
Our preferences and such
それぞれじゃん？
Are all different, right?
嫌いだよ
I hate you
喧嘩しても
Even if we fight
ずっと一緒だよね
We'll always be together
ルルリラ
Ru-ru-ri-ra
イエーイ！
Yeah!
メル先輩、ハッピーバースデー！
Mel-senpai, happy birthday!
アメにゃ、サンキュー！ センキュー、センキュー！
Amenya, thank you! Thank you, thank you!
一緒に歌って踊れて楽しかったよ。
It was so much fun to sing and dance together.
うー、メルも！ アメにゃ、今日はさ、
Woo, me too! Amenya, today is...
メルの誕生日だから、何かご褒美ちょうだい、プリーズ！
Mel's birthday, so give me a treat, please!
えー、何？ 何がいいかな？
Eh? What? What would be good?
あー、うー、ちょうだい！ プリーズ・キス・ミー！
Ah, woo, give me one! Please kiss me!
わお、メル先輩！
Wow, Mel-senpai!
大好き！
I love you!
わー、ミー・トゥー！
Whoa, me too!
アイ・ラブ・アメリア！
I love Amelia!
嬉しい！
I'm so happy!
これからも一緒に遊んでください。
Please keep hanging out with me from now on.
オフコース、アメリア。
Of course, Amelia.
あ、アイ・ウォン・テット・トゥ・ドゥー・サムシング・ウィズ・ユー。
Ah, I wanted to do something with you.
アメリアとやりたいことある。
There's something I want to do with Amelia.
何、何？
What, what?
えっとね、3rdフェスで踊ってたダンスが可愛かったから、一緒にやりたい。
Well, the dance you did at 3rd Fes was so cute, I want to do it together.
いい？
Is it okay?
いいよ。
Sure.
ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる。
Puru-puru, puru-puru.
せーの！
One, two!
ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる、ぷるぷる！
Wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle, wiggle!
イエーイ！
Yeah!
ダンス可愛かったよ。
The dance was cute.
ありがとう！ センキュー！
Thank you! Thank you!
エブリワン、テイク・ロッツ・オブ・ピクチャーズ、オーケー？
Everyone, take lots of pictures, okay?
いっぱい撮った？ 写真撮った？
Did you take a lot? Did you take photos?
ちょっと、アメリア、近くに。
Wait, Amelia, come closer.
カムカム... あ、ぎゅー！
Come, come... ah, hug!
チーズ！
Cheese!
ぎゅー、チーズ！
Hug, cheese!
おー、キュート！ キュート！
Oh, cute! Cute!
ウィー・アー・キュート！
We are cute!
メル先輩、本当に可愛い。めっちゃ可愛い！
Mel-senpai, you're really cute. Super cute!
アメリアも可愛いよ！
Amelia is cute too!
ありがとう。
Thank you.
ナイス・シスター！
Nice sister!
おー、ナイス・シスター。また遊ぼうね。
Oh, nice sister. Let's play together again.
あー、メル先輩、これからもよろしくね。
Ah, Mel-senpai, I look forward to more from now on.
よろしくね。
Likewise.
また遊びましょう。
Let's play again.
遊びましょう。これからもアメメルよろしく！
Let's play again. Keep supporting AmeMel!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelganger
作詞・作曲：kemu
Lyrics/Composition: kemu
どうもこんにちは君の分身です
Hello there, I'm your alter ego
何の冗談か目を擦ってみる
Thinking it's a joke, I rub my eyes
影が二つ伸びて
Two shadows stretch out
そしてまた幕が上がる
And once again, the curtain rises
もう一人自分がいたらなんて思いました？
Did you ever think, "What if there was another me?"
そんな純粋な願いが僕を呼んだのさ
That pure wish is what called out to me
そりゃ願ったとも
Well, of course I wished for it
艱難辛苦の全てを
If all my hardships and sufferings
代わってくれるなら
Could be taken over by someone else
過程はいいから結果をください
Forget the process, just give me the results
無意味で無意義な代償
Meaningless and pointless compensation
ねえこんな事より大事な事があるんだ
Hey, there's something more important than this
いいだろう
Very well
何をやらせようかなんでもやります
What should I have you do? "I'll do anything"
僕は君の分身です
I am your alter ego
含み笑いでサヨナラ
With a smirk, I say goodbye
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー　君は君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
混濁と交差して僕は誰？
Intertwined with confusion, who am I?
ねえ有りもしない　証明の根拠なんて何処にも
Hey, there's no ground for proof anywhere
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー　誰は誰は君
Dear Doppelganger, who is who is you
蝕まれた存在に世界は気付かない
The world doesn't notice the corroded existence
鳴り止まない　覚めもしない
It won't stop ringing, it won't wake up
奇跡の輪廻が狂った正解を染め上げてる　ルンパッパ
The samsara of miracles dyes the crazy answer, Runpappa
どうも失礼可笑しい月曜日
Excuse me, on this strange Monday
一つずつ消えてゆく真実が
The truths that disappear one by one
僕を詐称する
Are misrepresenting me
お前は一体...
Who on earth are you...
ちょっと待った 知らぬ間に独りぼっち
Wait a second, before I knew it, I was all alone
明日の予定も 知らない言葉
Tomorrow's plans, words I don't know
そりゃデタラメな 汚れ下げは解けていく
Well, that nonsensical, messy ending is dissolving
僕はなんなんだろうね
I wonder what I am
ねえどうか 存在を返して
Hey, please, give me back my existence
あいにく様だが こっちはこっちで
Pardon me, but over here, on this side
随分居心地が良くて
It's been quite comfortable
もうあなたの居場所は ここには前と
There's no longer a place for you here
わかってるんでしょ
You know that, don't you?
ねえバレたんなら 奪えばいいだろ
Hey, if I'm found out, I should just take it over
今度は僕の番だ
This time, it's my turn
含み笑いで 威張るな
Don't act so high and mighty with that smirk
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
嗚呼 混沌と交差して
Ah, intersecting with chaos
僕は誰？
Who am I?
さあ 狂騒と踊れば
Now, if we dance with the frenzy
命の椅子は一つだけ
There's only one seat for life
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 誰は君と僕を裂いた
Dear Doppelganger, who tore you and me apart?
一滴 渇き混ぜる前に
Before a single drop of thirst mixes in
何でもいい 何でもいい
Anything's fine, anything's fine
器をください
Give me a vessel
狂った正解が染め上げてる アンバッバ
The twisted truth is dyeing it all, An-ba-ba
それはずっと続く 人の子の連鎖
That is the chain of children of men that continues forever
委ね合って 許し合って 満たされ往く
Entrusting each other, forgiving each other, becoming fulfilled
欠けたピース 価値のペイン 渇望した愛も
The missing piece, the pain of value, even the craved love
託し合って 生まれ変わる イニシエーション
Entrusting to each other, a reborn initiation
僕の頬を ちゃんと君は射てるから
Since you're properly aiming at my cheek
君も次の誰か ちゃんと救わなくちゃ
You must properly save the next someone too
もうわかってんだろ 何をすればいいかさ
You already know what you should do, right?
どうか誰か僕に 奇跡をくれよ
Please, someone, give me a miracle
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー 君は君は誰？
Dear Doppelganger, who are you, who are you?
嗚呼 混沌と交差して 僕は誰？
Ah, intersecting with chaos, who am I?
もう止まらない 戻れない
Can't stop anymore, can't go back
どうもこんにちは 君の分身です
Hello there, I am your alter ego
拝啓ドッペルゲンガー
Dear Doppelganger
それはそれは僕を 縛り出した存在
That, that is the existence that tied me down
世界がいつか 鳴り止まないならば
If the world one day never stops ringing
奇跡の輪廻が 狂った世界を
If the cycle of miracles dyes the twisted world
染め上げるさ アンバッバ アンバッバ
It will dye it all, An-ba-ba An-ba-ba
「どうもこんにちは 君の分身です」
“Hello there, I am your alter ego”
ゴーストルール
Ghost Rule
作詞・作曲：DECO*27
Lyrics/Composition: DECO*27
どうだっていいことを 嘘吐いて吐いて 戻れない
Lying and lying about things that don't matter, I can't go back
時効なんてやってこない 奪ったように奪われて
The statute of limitations never comes, being stolen from just as I stole
今日だって叶わない 思ったように騙せない
Even today it doesn't come true, I can't deceive as I thought
腐っている僕には 腐ったものがわからない
For someone as rotten as me, I don't understand rotten things
おいで
Come here
ここまで
This far
いぇー
Yeah
隠してしまったんだ
I ended up hiding it
メーデー 僕とわかっても
Mayday, even if you know it's me
もう抱きしめなくていいんだよ
You don't have to hug me anymore
メーデー 僕がわかったら
Mayday, if you understand it's me
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll smile for me once more
マボロシだって知るんだよ
Knowing it's just a phantom
嘘憑きだって知るんだよ ねえ
Knowing I'm a liar too, hey
どうだっていいはずが 居取ってイエスを絞り出す
It should be fine either way, but I take a seat and squeeze out a 'yes'
後悔の静寂は 騙した方が正義なの
In the silence of regret, is the one who deceives the righteous one?
卑怯だって構わない 祈っておいてそれはない
I don't care if it's cowardly, you can't say that after praying
飾っていた饒舌が 墓穴を掘ってえらい様
The eloquence I decorated with dug its own grave; what a fine mess
おいで
Come here
どこまで
How far?
いぇー
Yeah
被害者面したって
Even if you act like the victim
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ
Mayday, expose me
正直者な夢見たいなら
If you want to see a dreamer who is honest
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ
Mayday, judge me
最後まで甘え尽かすのは
To rely on someone to the very end is...
亡霊だって知るんだよ
Knowing it's just a ghost
空白だって知るんだよ ねえ
Knowing it's just a void, hey
足りないものを望んだら 僕じゃない僕になった
If I desire what is missing, I become someone who isn't me
迷い込んだままの譲り合いで
Stuck in a stalemate of passing the buck
それでも前に進んだの
But still, I moved forward
クラクラしちゃう夜も
Through nights that make my head spin
足りない僕を愛してよ
Love me, even though I'm not enough
歪んだまま僕を汚してよ
Taint me, even as I'm warped
君には僕が見えるかな
I wonder if you can see me
孤独なピエロが
The lonely pierrot
メーデー 僕と判っても
Mayday, even if you realize it's me
もう抱き締めなくていいんだよ
you don't have to hold me anymore
メーデー 僕が解ったら
Mayday, if you understand me
もう一度笑ってくれるかな
I wonder if you'll smile for me once more
メーデー 僕を叱ってよ
Mayday, scold me
正直者が夢見たいなら
if an honest person wants to dream
メーデー 僕を裁いてよ
Mayday, judge me
最後まで甘えてしまうのは
that I'd depend on you until the end
メーデー 僕を暴いてよ
Mayday, expose me
もう時期終わるこの世界から
from this world that's about to end
メーデー 僕と踊ってよ
Mayday, dance with me
最初からいないと解ってた
I knew from the start I wasn't here
どうだっていい言を
I spit out words that don't matter
嘘って吐いて戻れない
and can't go back
時効なんてやってこない
The statute of limitations will never come
奪った様に奪われて
Having things taken as I took them
わー！メル先輩！
Wow! Mel-senpai!
お誕生日おめでとうございます！
Happy birthday!
あー！ありがとう、こよちゃん！
Ah! Thank you, Koyo-chan!
いや、ホント一緒に歌えて嬉しいですよ、メル。
I'm really happy we could sing together.
嬉しい！
I'm happy too!
あー、ありがとうございます。
Ah, thank you so much.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
なんですけど、ちょっと、こよりメル先輩に
But, I have something I want to ask
この機会にちょっと聞きたいことがあるんですが...
Mel-senpai on this occasion...
なに？
What is it?
もうなんか、こよりとはワンナイトとかツーナイトとか、
I mean, you were saying things like "one night" or "two nights" with Koyori...
つま言ってたじゃないですか。
before, didn't you?
あー、ね、あったね、そんなこと。
Ah, yeah, I did say that.
そこんところどうなんですか、結局、
What's the deal with that? What do you actually...
こよのことどう思ってるんですか？
think of Koyo?
え？
Eh?
あー、こより。何言ってんだ。
Ah, Koyori. What are you saying?
もう、初めてのお風呂も、その他諸々、
Our first bath together, and everything else...
こよりが初めてなんだぜ。
Koyori was my first.
もう、それってどういう意味か、わかるよな。
You know what that means, right?
ちょっと、急にイケボで、え？あー！
Wait, a sudden cool voice? Eh? Ah!
だあ！
Dah!
あ、あー！
Ah, ah!
よし。
Alright.
うー、なんか今聞こえた気がするけど、今、心の声。
Ugh, I feel like I just heard something... like your inner thoughts.
あ、こよちゃん、こよちゃん、そうだった。
Ah, Koyo-chan, Koyo-chan, that's right.
せっかくさ、二人でコラボなんだから、一緒に何か写真撮ろうよ。
Since we're doing this collab together, let's take a photo together.
あ、撮ります！
Ah, let's do it!
なんか流された気がするけど、はい！
I feel like I'm being swept along, but okay!
はい、撮りましょう、撮りましょう。
Yes, let's take one, let's take one.
撮ろう！やったー！
Let's! Yay!
やったー！
Yay!
何撮ろうかな。
What should we do?
どうしましょうか。
じゃあ、連名、メルコヨだから我らね。
Well, we're "Mel-Koyo", the collective name.
はいはい。
Right, right.
ま、それっぽいポーズ撮らん？
Shall we take a pose that looks like that?
あ、いいですね。
Ah, that sounds good.
そしたら... じゃああれかな。
In that case... maybe that one.
あれだね、きっと。
That one, surely.
あれだね、きっと、もし。
That one, surely, if...
行っていいのかな。
Should we go for it?
行っていいかな。
Should we?
じゃあ背中合わせにして...
Then, back to back...
あ、はいはいはい。
Ah, yes, yes, yes.
かっこよく決めよう。
Let's strike a cool pose.
オッケーです！
Okay!
行くよ。
Here we go.
はい。
Yes.
せーの！
One, two...
真実は...
The truth is...
偽りは...
The fiction is...
ひとつ！
One!
お、かっこいい。
Oh, cool.
かっこいい！
Cool!
決まったんじゃない？みんなバシャバシャ撮ってね。
Didn't we nail it? Everyone, take lots of pictures.
撮ってください！
Please take some!
おー、いいねいいね。これは謎が解けるぞ。
Oh, nice, nice. This will solve the mystery.
もうこれは名探偵の「め」も迷うじゃなくて、名前の「な」になりそうですね。
This isn't just the 'Me' of Master Detective being puzzled, it's becoming the 'Na' of his name.
そうだそうだ。
That's right, that's right.
じゃあ次は...
Then next...
はい、なんかいいですか？
Yes, do you have something?
あの...
Um...
何なに？
What what?
可愛いで、あの、ちょっとね、
Something cute, um, just to make sure...
ちゃんとこよりとはもうワンナイトとか言わせないために、
...you won't say things like "one night" with Koyori anymore,
なんかギューって感じの、証拠写真撮らせてもらっていいですか？
can I take a "huggy" type of evidence photo?
おー！いいんだけど。
Oh! That's fine.
ちょっとね、流された感じしたんでね。
Since I felt like I was swept along before.
あー、ね。
Ah, I see.
じゃあ、いいですか？ギューってしてみて。
Then, is it okay? Let's try a hug.
えい、やったー！
Yay!
ギュー！
Huuug!
恥ずかしい、ギュー。
Embarrassing... hug.
あー、ドキドキ伝わってくる気がする。
Ah, I feel like I can sense your heart racing.
お風呂も入ったけど、ギューは初めてだよ、こよちゃんと。
We've taken a bath together, but this is the first time hugging you, Koyo-chan.
あ、こよも、あ...
Ah, Koyo too... ah...
撮られてるみんな、大勢に見られて撮られている...
Everyone is taking pictures... we're being seen and photographed by so many...
ちょっと、それなんかちょっと、なんかえっちなんで。
Wait, that's somehow... a bit lewd.
何考えてんの、もう。
What are you thinking, honestly?
う、何でもないです、何でもないです。
Ugh, it's nothing, it's nothing.
こよちゃん、今日本当にありがとう、
Koyo-chan, thank you so much for today.
一緒に歌えてメルもうめちゃくちゃ嬉しかったよ。
Mel was so incredibly happy to sing with you.
いや、こよのほうこそです。
No, it's me who should be thanking you.
これからも、ラブラブしていきましょうね。
Let's keep being lovey-dovey from now on too.
してこうね。
Let's do that.
やったー！こんこよー！
Yay! Kon-Koyo!
こんこよー、こんこよー、こんかっぷー！
Kon-Koyo, Kon-Koyo, Kon-Kapu!
HANAJI
作詞：有森聡美　作曲：村井聖夜
Lyrics: Satomi Arimori, Composition: Seiya Murai
ハッとしてハッとして
Startled and startled
ハッとしてリン！
Startled and Rin!
ハッとしてハッとして
Startled and startled
ハッとしてリン！
Startled and Rin!
ワクワク
Exciting
ギュッとしてジャン
Squeeze and Jan
ギュッとしちゃう
I'll squeeze
鼻血、ハッハハイショ！！
Nosebleed, ha ha ha!
運命の子を 探しに来たけど
I came looking for the child of fate
目移り腕まくり
But I'm distracted, sleeves rolled up
ピーシャバジャの花が 満開全開
The flowers are in full bloom
幸せ咲き乱れ
Happiness blooms in profusion
なぜか秘め事を 分け合う奴に
For some reason, to those who share secrets
お戯れ気味ですの
You're feeling playful
アイツに会うと
When I meet him
カミングアウト
Coming out
攻められ イジられ やめてやめて ア～ハン
Attacked, teased, stop it, stop it, ah-han
恋、目覚めて
Love, awakening
振り回されて
Being swung around
アメとムチ ハイパーなポンズ
Carrot and stick, hyper ponzu
逃げたいくらい イジめられちゃう
I'm teased so much I want to run away
だけど代わったいフなの
But I'm different
ポンズ
Ponzu
ハッとしてハッとして
Startled and startled
ハッとしてワクワク
Startled and excited
ギュッとしてギュッとしちゃう
Squeeze and squeeze
鼻血、ハッハイショ！！
Nosebleed, ha ha ha!
まだまだだ 絶好調だね
Not yet, I'm in top form
似合いもうきまくり
It suits me perfectly
ハメの状態 無視毛は世も末
Stuck, the ignored hairs are the end of the world
されても乗りまくり
Even if it's done, I'm riding high
立ち止まらないの 心のハトで
I won't stop, in the heart of my heart
フワッとしずか見
Looking gently and quietly
ピクピクアウト
Twitch twitch out
カミングアウト
Coming out
キスにキスに 溺れすぎの ア～ハン
Too many kisses, too many kisses, ah-han
めぐりできたて
Newly arrived
ベイビーおるて
Baby Orte
持て遊ぶのが 趣味なの
Toying around is my hobby
わかっていても ののしられても
Even if I know, even if I'm cursed
だけどマジにうついちゃう
But I'm seriously getting into it
なぜか秘め事を 分け合う奴に
For some reason, to those who share secrets
お戯れ気味ですの
You're feeling playful
アイツに会うと
When I meet him
カミングアウト
Coming out
攻められ イジられ やめてやめて ア～ハン
Attacked, teased, stop it, stop it, ah-han
恋、目覚めて
Love, awakening
振り回されて
Being swung around
アメとムチ ハイパーなポンズ
Carrot and stick, hyper ponzu
逃げたいくらい イジめられちゃう
I'm teased so much I want to run away
だけど代わったいフなの
But I'm different
ポンズ
Ponzu
ハッとしてハッとして
Startled and startled
ハッとしてワクワク
Startled and excited
ギュッとしてギュッとしちゃう
Squeeze and squeeze
鼻血、ハッハイショ！！
Nosebleed, ha ha ha!
おやったー！ おやったー！
We did it! We did it!
ちょうどさ 去年の誕生日ライブにも
マリン来てくれたよね
By the way, Marine came to my
birthday live last year too, right?
そうだお！ メルちゃ！
That's right! Mel-cha!
ねえさ…もしかして
マリンのこと好き？
Say... do you perhaps...
like Marine?
えっ？
Eh?
おろっちょっと、引いてんじゃないお！
Oh, hey, don't be repulsed!
えへへ。でもまあ、メルね
マリンともっと遊びたいと思ってるお！
Ehehe. But well, Mel
wants to play more with Marine!
おお！
Oh!
人間界にも最近来たばっかだし
I've just come to the human world recently...
今度はさ、うちに来ないか？ マリン
Next time, why don't you come to my house, Marine?
メ、メルちゃんちに！？
一体何されちゃうの！？
Me-Mel-chan's house?!
What on earth are you going to do to me?!
え？ こないだの続きに決まってるでしょ
Eh? It's decided to be a continuation of the other day.
なんすか続き、こないだこないだとか
ちょっと過去すぎて忘れたんだけど何すか続き
What's the continuation?! The other day...
it's too far in the past, I forgot! What was it?!
マリン、自分から誘っておいてひどいお！
Marine, you invited me first, didn't you?
えっ、誘っ、メルちゃん自意識過剰だな
別に誘ってないんだけど
Eh?! Invited?! Mel-chan, you're over-self-conscious!
I didn't invite you!
さ、誘ってたお！ 即落ちしたじゃん！
秒だったじゃん！
You did! You did it immediately!
It was in a flash!
おお、まあちょっと忘れてるけど
今度は、メルちゃんち、行こうかなぁ
Oh... well, I forgot a bit, but
next time, Mel-chan's house... maybe I'll go.
やったー！ 決まりだお！
Yay! It's a promise!
メルもマジでマリンのこと好きだな。困ったなー
Mel really likes Marine. I'm in trouble.
はいはいはい。じゃあさ
せっかく久しぶりに二人で3Dライブだから
Yes, yes, yes. Then...
since it's a rare 3D live for the two of us...
なんかポーズ一緒に取ろう！
Let's take a pose together!
ああいいおいいお、どんなポーズにする？
Oh, okay! What kind of pose should we do?
そうだおね。さっきのなんか曲中だとなんか
Well... like the one in the middle of the song...
さっきメルちゃんと立場で逆マリンだったから
Because earlier Mel-chan and I had our roles reversed.
あ、確かに。ちょっと逆のも見たいかな。
Ah, that's true. I kind of want to see the opposite too.
マリン様？
Marine-sama?
じゃあちょっとスーパーダーリン見せるか。
Then, shall I show you my Super Darling side?
いや、でもさ、SM系の方がいいのかな？
No, wait, maybe an SM type is better?
そうだね。ちょっと精一杯のマリンのいじめを見たいかな。
Right. I want to see Marine bullying me with all her might.
あ、なるほど。じゃあちょっとメルちゃん、ちょっと歯食いしばってもらってもいいかな？
Ah, I see. Then, Mel-chan, could you please grit your teeth for a moment?
え？バシーン！
Eh? *Slap!*
あ！
Ah!
メル、この豚！
Mel, you pig!
この豚！ブヒ！
You pig! Oink!
メル、跪きなさい！跪き！
Mel, kneel down! Kneel!
あ、痛いよ。
Ah, it hurts.
あ、でもこれ、これがこれがこれがいいんでしょ？
Ah, but this... this is what's good, right?
あ、好きです！
Ah, I love it!
あー気持ちいいです。
Ah, it feels good.
あ、やっぱ好きなんだ。あ、これ気持ちいいのね。ブヒ！
Ah, so you do like it. Ah, this feels good, doesn't it? Oink!
あ、こんな変態とはお友達でいられません！
Ah, I can't be friends with such a pervert anymore!
お前もド変態だろうが！
You're a total pervert too!
ちょっとバレちゃったな。ちょっと、なんかただれてきた。
Ah, I guess I'm found out. Things are getting a bit messy.
なんか汚い空気になってきたから、可愛いポーズ取ろうか。ね。
The air is getting a bit dirty, so let's take a cute pose. Okay?
あ、そうだね。ラストはちょっと可愛く決めましょうか。
Ah, you're right. Let's finish with a cute pose.
仲良しで。うんうん。
As good friends. Yeah.
え、じゃあさ、一緒にさ、ちょっと二人愛し合ってるってことが完全に判明したから。
Well then, since it's been completely proven that we love each other...
ハート作ろうか。オッケー。
Let's make a heart. Okay.
ハートね。一緒に。
A heart. Together.
二人で。お願いよ。はい。それでは、はい、せーの！
The two of us. Ready? Okay, here we go. One, two...
イエーイ！
Yay!
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess
そういう扱い心得てよね
Make sure you know how to treat me like that
よね
Right?
ワールドイズマイン 作詞・作曲：ryo
World is Mine Lyrics/Composition: ryo
その一　いつもと違う髪形に気がつくこと
Number one: Notice when my hairstyle is different from usual
その二　ちゃんと靴まで見ること　いいね？
Number two: Make sure you look all the way down to my shoes, okay?
その三　わたしの一言には三つの言葉で返事すること
Number three: Reply with three words for every one of mine
わかったら右手がお留守なのをなんとかして！
If you understand, do something about my empty right hand!
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
キミに心から思ってほしいの　かわいいって
I just want you to think from your heart that I'm cute
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess
気がついて　ねえねえ
Notice me, hey, hey
待たせるなんて論外よ
Keeping me waiting is out of the question
わたしを誰だと思ってるの？
Who do you think I am?
もう何だか　甘いものが食べたい！
I just really want to eat something sweet!
いますぐによ
Right now!
ああ！
Ah!
Check one, two!
欠点？かわいいの間違いでしょ
Faults? You must mean 'cute'
文句は許しませんの
I won't allow any complaints
あのね、わたしの話ちゃんと聞いてる？ちょっと…
Hey, are you listening to me? Hey...
あ、それとね　白いおうまさん　決まってるでしょ？
Oh, and also, a white horse. It's obvious, right?
迎えに来て
Come pick me up
わかったら膝ついて手を取って「おひめさま」って
If you understand, kneel, take my hand and call me 'Princess'
べつにわがままなんて言ってないんだから
It's not like I'm being selfish or anything
でもね　少しくらい叱ってくれたっていいのよ？
But you know, it's okay to scold me just a little bit
世界でわたしだけのおうじさま
The world's only prince just for me
気がついて　ほらほら
Notice me, look, look
おててが空いてます
My hand is empty
無口で無愛想なおうじさま
A quiet and blunt prince
もうどうして！
Oh, why!
気がついてよ早く
Notice me quickly
ああ！
Ah!
絶対キミはわかってない
You definitely don't understand
わかってないわ…
You don't understand...
いちごの乗ったショートケーキ
Strawberry shortcake
こだわりたまごのとろけるプリン
Melting pudding made with special eggs
みんな　みんな　我慢します…
I'll endure them all...
わがままな子だと思わないで
Don't think of me as a selfish girl
わたしだってやればできるもん
I can do it if I try
あとで後悔するわよ
You'll regret it later
当然です！だってわたしは
Of course! Because I am
世界で一番おひめさま
The world's number one princess
ちゃんと見ててよね
Look at me properly
どこかに行っちゃうよ？
Or I'll go somewhere else
ふいに抱きしめられた　急にそんな　えっ？
Suddenly I was hugged. So suddenly, eh?
...れる
...me?
あどけないの？
Am I being innocent?
その一口が危ないわよ
That bite is dangerous!
放置するのが危ないわよ
Leaving me alone is dangerous!
あぅ！
Ah!
へへっ！
Hehe!
みんなー！
Everyone!
こんかっぷー！
Kon-kapu!
ライブ楽しんでるー？
Are you enjoying the live?
いっぱい歌ったね。
I sang a lot, didn't I?
めちゃくちゃ楽しんでるよメルは。
Mel is having so much fun.
今年のハロウィンも誕生日もみんなのおかげで、めっちゃ楽しい！
This Halloween and my birthday are both so fun thanks to everyone!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
でね、今回のステージ、もう気づいてくれたかな？
So, did you notice the stage this time?
今回もね、メル仕様に、なんと作っていただきました！
They actually made it specifically for Mel again!
ドドーン！可愛いでしょ？
Ta-da! It's cute, right?
すごいでしょ？
Amazing, right?
ねー、めちゃくちゃ可愛い。
Right? It's incredibly cute.
今日はね、いつもよりも、すごい告知があります。
Today, I have a bigger announcement than usual.
それはこの後説明するので、ぜひ最後まで聞いていってください。
I'll explain it after this, so please listen until the end.
まずはー、
First of all...
デレデデン！夜空メル誕生日記念グッズ 2022！
Ta-da-da-da! Yozora Mel Birthday Celebration Goods 2022!
夜空メル 誕生記念2022
10月31日 販売開始
Yozora Mel Birthday Celebration 2022
Sales start Oct. 31st
今回も、可愛いグッズをいっぱい用意してます。
We've prepared lots of cute goods again.
その一！
Number one!
夜空メルバースデーライト ～LEDアクリルスタンドライト～になってます。
The Yozora Mel Birthday Light LED Acrylic Stand.
あさぎゆな先生、書き下ろしのイラストだよ。
It's an original illustration by Asagi Yuna-sensei.
かっこいいでしょ？
Cool, right?
なんか、いつも可愛いメルだけど、
Even though Mel is usually just cute,
今回はかっこ可愛いメルに描いていただきましたー！
this time I was drawn as "cool-cute"!
お部屋でね、ぜひ使ってください。
Please use it in your room.
そして、その二！
And number two!
魔界の晩餐会グラス。これはワイングラスです。
The Demon Realm Banquet Glass. This is a wine glass.
これねメル、ずっと作りたかったんだよねー。
Mel has always wanted to make this.
メルは、アセロラジュースを入れて飲むつもりだけど、
I plan to put acerola juice in it, but
みんなはワインとか、ぶどうジュースとか入れて、ぜひ、
everyone, please put in wine or grape juice and
「うーむ、そう...」って言って飲んでください。
say, "Hmm, I see..." while drinking.
いっぱい使ってね。
Use it a lot, okay?
その三！
Number three!
メルの魔導書パスケース。これはパスケースになってます。
Mel's Grimoire Pass Case. This is a pass case.
日常でぜひ、いっぱい使ってほしいな。
I hope you use it a lot in your daily life.
実はね、この本の柄、
Actually, this book's pattern
今後ね、メルの配信や「歌ってみた」などで、今後出てくる予定があります。
is planned to appear in future streams and song covers.
何かでは、ちょっと今内緒なんだけど、
I'll keep what it is a secret for now, but
その時のお楽しみということで、みなさんぜひ先取りで、ゲットしてほしいな。
look forward to it, and I hope you get it ahead of time.
そして、次がビッグなお知らせ。その四！
And next is a big announcement. Number four!
夜空メル 1stアルバム 『Twinkle Star Magic☆』です！
Yozora Mel 1st Album "Twinkle Star Magic☆"!
これは、ぜひゲットしてほしい。もう、一番ゲットしてほしいやつ。
I really want you to get this. It's the one I want you to get the most.
かっこいい曲からね、可愛い曲、しっとり曲などなどいっぱい詰め込みました。
It's packed with cool songs, cute songs, mellow songs, and more.
いろんなメルを知ってほしいなって思って、たくさん詰め込んだので、ぜひ聴いてほしいです。
I wanted you to know different sides of Mel, so I packed a lot in.
全部でなんと、トゥルン！ 11曲あります。
There are actually... ta-da! 11 songs in total.
メルね、5ヶ月連続でオリ曲リリースしてたんですけど、
I've been releasing original songs for five consecutive months,
『かぷっとNight☆Sky』から、今までのオリ曲、
from "Kapputto Night☆Sky" to my other originals,
そしてね、まだ配信されてない曲が、なんと5曲も入って、
and it includes 5 songs that haven't been released yet,
合計11曲になってます。
for a total of 11 songs.
さらに、メルの初めてのオリ曲『かぷっとNight☆Sky』のリミックスバージョンも入っています。
Furthermore, it includes a remix version of my first original song.
さらに、さらに、
And, and,
『レイニー・ダイアリー』の夜空メル歌唱バージョンも入ってます。
it also includes my solo version of "Rainy Diary".
これはねメル、一人でね、5役、演じて歌いました。
For this, Mel played five different roles while singing.
めちゃ頑張ったから、聴いてください。
I worked really hard on it, so please listen.
お姉さんボイスとか少年ボイスとかね、そんな感じで歌ったので聴いてください。よろしくお願いします。
I used voices like a mature sister and a young boy, so please listen.
で今回ね、グッズ全部買ってくれた人には今回も特典があります。
And for those who buy all the goods, there's a bonus this time too.
一つ目は、メルからのラブレターです。
First is a love letter from Mel.
これは初めてかもしれないね。
This might be a first.
その二！ ASMRボイス。うん。
Number two! ASMR voice.
こっちもね、あまあまになってるので、合わせて、ぜひ全部合わせてね、あの、聴いて見てください。
This is also super sweet, so please check it out along with the other goods.
ゼッゼ... めちゃ噛んだ。
Ze-ze... I totally stumbled over my words.
もう歌いまくってさ、もう呼吸が、
I've been singing so much, I'm out of breath...
いっぱいぜひゲットしてください。
Please get them!
ちょっとグッズ告知長くなっちゃったけど、
The goods announcement went on for a bit, but
今日はこの後メンバー限定でね、
after this today, for members only,
アフターライブ、アフターライブやります！
I'll be doing an after-live, an after-live!
あと、一緒に、もうちょっとだけ、一緒にいたいなと思って...
Also, I thought I'd like to be together, just a little bit longer...
予定作ったんだけど、メルと一緒にいてくれますか？
I made a schedule, will you stay with Mel?
やったー！
Yay!
約束だよ！
It's a promise!
じゃ、次が、最後の曲になります。
Well then, the next one will be the last song.
きっともう、カプ民のみんななら、合いの手ね、バッチリだよね？
I'm sure that if you're all Kapu-min, you'll be perfect with the calls, right?
バッチリだよね？大丈夫だよね？
You'll be perfect, right? You'll be fine, right?
知らないよーって人いたら、まあ、このあとね、
If there's anyone who says "I don't know it," well, after this...
ダウンロードしてください。
Please download it.
めっちゃいい曲なので、聞いてほしいです。
It's a really good song, so I want you to listen to it.
今日もね、本当に本当に、ありがとう、カプ民のみんな。
Today too, really, really, thank you, everyone in the Kapu-min.
大好きだよ！
I love you!
カプー！
Kapu-!
じゃ、メルは、こっちで歌っちゃおー！
Well then, Mel's going to sing over here!
星の数より、お菓子の数だけ
Instead of the number of stars, just the number of sweets
それは、切分？
Is that a moment?
お菓子をちょーだい！
Give me sweets!
お化け、かき分け、夜を駆けてゆく
Pushing through the ghosts, running through the night
わたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire
ぱっぱらパンプキンが、微笑めて
Papara pumpkin smiles
てってれ、照れちゃって
Tettere, getting shy
可愛いいな
So cute
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんもお年頃
Jack-o'-lantern is also at that age
ドキドキしてるの、わかるかな？
Can you tell my heart is pounding?
近づいて
Come closer
1, 2, 3
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
がぷっとしたら
If I take a bite
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
るんるんるん
Run run run
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、カプうぃん
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, Kapu-win
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、with you
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, with you
魔女、フランケン、悪魔、ミイラ、ゾンビ
Witch, Franken, Devil, Mummy, Zombie
オーマが時の、大物ぞろい
A lineup of big shots at the magic hour
PLEASE TRICK
Ah お腹がすくの、何でかな？
Ah, why am I getting hungry?
ワクワクしてるよ、いざ Party Night
I'm so excited, now for the Party Night
お耳カプカプ、お腹タップタップ
Munch munching on the ears, tap tapping on the belly
たくさんちょーだい！
Give me lots!
気配、かき分け、夜を駆けてゆく
Pushing through the presence, running through the night
わたしヴァンパイア
I'm a vampire
1, 2, 3
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
がぷっとしたら
If I take a bite
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
るんるんるん
Run run run
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、カプうぃん
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, Kapu-win
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、with you
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, with you
キュートが過ぎちゃって、ごめんね！
I'm sorry for being too cute!
ボンキュッボンで、セクシーポーズ、かわいい！
Bon-kyu-bon with a sexy pose, so cute!
あなたの心とカラダに、メル！メル！
To your heart and body, Mel! Mel!
魔界の？最強！天才！最強！かわいい！
Underworld's? Strongest! Genius! Strongest! Cute!
ヴァンパイアってー？夜空メル！
A vampire is...? Yozora Mel!
ぱっぱらパンプキンは、どこにいる？
Where is the papara pumpkin?
とっとと遠くまで、行こうよ
Let's go far away quickly
ジャック・オー・ランタンくんの浮気者
Jack-o'-lantern, you cheater
ボコボコにして、連れて帰る、覚悟して
I'll beat you up and take you home, be prepared
1, 2, 3
離さないよ、離さないよ
I won't let go, I won't let go
いつまでも、ずっと、一緒がいいな
I want to be together forever and ever
このお祭り、共に過ごそう
Let's spend this festival together
ハロウィン、ハロウィン、ハロウィン
Halloween, Halloween, Halloween
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
がぷっとしたら
If I take a bite
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
るんるんるん
Run run run
Oh ハローハロー Win-win
Oh hello hello Win-win
そんなカンケイ
That kind of relationship
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、カプうぃん
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, Kapu-win
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、with you
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, with you
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、Chu！
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, Chu!
カプうぃん、カプうぃん、大好きだー！
Kapu-win, Kapu-win, I love you!
たくさんのお祝いありがとう！！
Thank you for all the celebrations!!
これからもずっとよろしくね♡ だいすきだよっ♡
Please continue to support me forever♡ I love you so much♡